<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on My Month in Mulki</title>
    <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on My Month in Mulki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mulki.samhattangady.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Initiative</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Hey Adi, I need to talk to you.&amp;rdquo;
Adi looked up at me from his bowl of chickpeas, with that everpresent mischevious glint in his eye.
&amp;ldquo;Go ahead bro, tell me.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Not here man, it&amp;rsquo;s a little serious. Can we speak after lunch?&amp;rdquo;
The glint in his eye dimmed by half a degree, but his smile seemed unfamiliar with the concept of fading.
&amp;ldquo;Oh. Serious&amp;hellip; Sure bro, let&amp;rsquo;s meet outside.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Opportunity</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Bhai, chalo, get up. We&amp;rsquo;re going for camping tonight, se we&amp;rsquo;ll all go to the beach and chill by the campfire.&amp;rdquo;
Khan is standing hunched over me, his hair lazily hunched over his face.
&amp;ldquo;Dude, I just got here this morning. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t even able to sleep in the bus. And lot of work was also there today na. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll just crash today. I&amp;rsquo;ll come next time.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Bhai, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to Mulki now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Patience</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Vivek. How do you know which is a good spot to surf? Like where should we be waiting, and how deep in the water?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Sam, look out there. In the waves. See how they are coming in a pattern? Those are called sets. Those are the waves that we want to ride. So just keep looking out towards the ocean. Can you see the swells coming towards us? &amp;hellip; See there&amp;rsquo;s one set right there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Ambition</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Sammy bro, what happened bro?&amp;rdquo;
I am suddenly snapped back to my senses. I look around and see that most of the boys are no longer with us on the verandah. It&amp;rsquo;s just me and Guru now, sitting outside. It&amp;rsquo;s the middle of the afternoon, but we&amp;rsquo;re under the shade of some trees, and there is a cool breeze that is determined to keep us there.
&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know Guru. Nothing really went right while surfing today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: Sincerity </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter5/</guid>
      <description>Volunteering is a different kind of experience. For those familiar with concepts of Game Theory, a lot of interesting situations tend to arise. Theoretically, the situations arise regardless of whether one is aware of the mathematical concepts behind them, but I guess I&amp;rsquo;m enough of a nerd to enjoy viewing these kinds of scenarios through theoretical lenses.
In the case of Mulki at least, us volunteers don&amp;rsquo;t specifically have duties assigned to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: Interaction </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter6/</guid>
      <description>One of the more interesting features (though probably accidental) of the surfing school&amp;rsquo;s design, was that the rooms themselves are not neccessarily the most comfortable spaces to spend time. The common areas however, with their excellent views, comfortable seating, and perpetual stiff breezes, tend to be exponentially more ideal gathering spots.
Thus, most guests, and most volunteers tend to use their rooms just to sleep. Most of the free time is spent outside, in the common areas, together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: Experiment </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Sam, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been active at any point in my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve not really played any sports. I know how to swim, but have never really done much of it. I&amp;rsquo;m a little overweight, and better described as middle-aged than young&amp;hellip; Do you think I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to surf?&amp;rdquo;
Ashok looks at me, and I sense some genuine worry in his voice. We are on the boat that is taking us towards the beach, and he is about to get to surf for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion: Learning </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>I was really fortunate to have been able to take up an opportunity like this. I realise that something like this is not neccessarily available to all, and not everyone can actually make use of it. So while I have the privelege to be able to avail this, I also have a duty, in some cosmic sense, to actually make the most use of it. I hope I was able to fulfill that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue: Adventure</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/epilogue/</guid>
      <description>The universe works in funny ways sometimes. I spent my month in Mulki, and was quite happy with the time I got to spend, and the lessons that I got to learn. But as it turned out, my whole month was more of an opportunity to study for a final exam that had probably been planned all along.
The exam came in the form of an opportunity for an adventure. But in order to be able to actually see the opportunity for what it was, and then be able to accept it, I needed to have learnt all the lessons that were part of my syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Chapters</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapters/</guid>
      <description>I guess theoretically the lessons are all independent of each other, and the chapters can be read in any order. So go ahead.
Chapter 1: Initiative Chapter 2: Opportunity Chapter 3: Patience Chapter 4: Ambition Chapter 5: Sincerity Chapter 6: Interaction Chapter 7: Experiment Conclusion: Learning Epilogue: Adventure </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
