<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on My Month in Mulki</title>
    <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on My Month in Mulki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mulki.samhattangady.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Initiative</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Hey Adi, I need to talk to you.&amp;rdquo;
Adi looked up at me from his bowl of chickpeas, with that everpresent mischevious glint in his eye.
&amp;ldquo;Go ahead bro, tell me.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Not here man, it&amp;rsquo;s a little serious. Can we speak after lunch?&amp;rdquo;
The glint in his eye dimmed by half a degree, but his smile seemed unfamiliar with the concept of fading.
&amp;ldquo;Oh. Serious&amp;hellip; Sure bro, let&amp;rsquo;s meet outside.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Opportunity</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Bhai, chalo, get up. We&amp;rsquo;re going for camping tonight, se we&amp;rsquo;ll all go to the beach and chill by the campfire.&amp;rdquo;
Khan is standing hunched over me, his hair lazily hunched over his face.
&amp;ldquo;Dude, I just got here this morning. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t even able to sleep in the bus. And lot of work was also there today na. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll just crash today. I&amp;rsquo;ll come next time.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Bhai, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to Mulki now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Patience</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Vivek. How do you know which is a good spot to surf? Like we should be waiting, and how deep in the water?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Sam, look out there. In the waves. See how they are coming in a pattern? Those are called sets. Those are the waves that we want to ride. So just keep looking out towards the ocean. Can you see the swells coming towards us? &amp;hellip; See there&amp;rsquo;s one set right there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Ambition</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Sammy bro, what happened bro?&amp;rdquo;
I am suddenly snapped back to my senses. I look around and see that most of the boys are no longer sitting on the verandah. They&amp;rsquo;ve all headed inside to participate in their chosen kind of worship to Lord Shiva. It&amp;rsquo;s just me and Guru now, sitting outside. It&amp;rsquo;s the middle of the afternoon, but we&amp;rsquo;re sitting under the shade of some trees, and there is a cool breeze keeping us there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: Sincerity </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter5/</guid>
      <description>Volunteering is an interesting experience. For those familiar with concepts of Game Theory and such, a lot of interesting situations tend to arise. Theoretically, the situations arise regardless of whether one is aware of the mathematical concepts behind them, but I guess I&amp;rsquo;m enough of a nerd to enjoy viewing scenarios in my life through theoretical lenses.
In the case of Mulki at least, us volunteers don&amp;rsquo;t specifically have duties assigned to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: --- </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter6/</guid>
      <description>Effort leads to reward. Interacting with people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: --- </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/chapter7/</guid>
      <description>There is no indicator to what makes a person good at surfing, apart from actually going out there and surfing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion: --- </title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>conclusion things. maybe merge epilogue here? potatoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue: Adventure</title>
      <link>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:13:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mulki.samhattangady.com/epilogue/</guid>
      <description>The universe works in funny ways sometimes. I spent my month in Mulki, and was quite happy with the time I got to spend, and the lessons that I got to learn. But as it turned out, my whole month was more of an opportunity to study for a final exam that had probably been planned all along.
The exam came in the form of an opportunity for an adventure. But in order to be able to actually see the opportunity for what it was, and then be able to accept it, I needed to have learnt all the lessons that were part of my syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
